(creaking)
(wind whistling)
(water lapping)
(gull cries)
(creaking)
(water rippling, gull squawks)
(engine rumbling)
(tyres crunching)
(handbrake clicks, engine cuts)
(car door opens)
(wind howling)
(gate, chains clanking)
(wind whistling, creaking)
Jesus Christ!
(creaking)
(dripping)
She's back.
(slow dramatic music)
(birds singing)
(dogs barking)
(youth shouting)
(clock ticking)
I know 'tis hard but...
we've gotta decide what to do.
Tina?
(slow dramatic music)
(grass rustling)
(heavy breathing)
(dog barking distantly)
(leaves rustling)
(slow dramatic music continues)
(birds squawking)
(seagulls crying)
(van rumbling loudly)
(melancholic music)
(waves crashing)
(whooshing)
Mr Richards?
(thunder cracks, rain pouring)
Emily?
What?
Oh, Mrs Richards!
Come on. Let's get you in.
Okay?
(rain clanking on gutter)
(music tinkling)
TELEVISION: Hello there.
How are you today?
I hope you're feeling
super-duper.
I know I am.
Do you know why?
Because...
it's making time!
It's my favourite time
of the week.
(water dripping)
(clanking)
(louder dripping)
(Mrs Richards sighs)
(television continues playing)
(stool scrapes)
Hark...
My boy's coming home.
(dark music)
(heavy rain)
MIKE: So, we gonna try again?
(creaking)
Are we?
(rain pattering)
(creaking)
(suspenseful music)
We keep this between us.
Who's gonna crew?
There ent no-one left here,
Mike.
(torrential rain)
(drip gets faster)
(rain pattering hard)
Sorry!
(pouring)
(television continues)
(ominous music)
(door bangs)
(splash)
EMILY: There he is.
(splosh)
Right, Mrs Richards.
Nick'll take you home.
(Mrs Richard groans)
(rain pouring outside)
(thunder rumbles)
(footsteps receding quietly)
(clock ticking)
She d'get the past and present
mixed up.
They caught some fish that day.
Different place this was
back then.
Harbour full of boats,
trucks, men.
Fulla life.
Three year Luke
was on that boat.
He never went again.
Guilt's hard shadow
to live under.
(clock ticking intensifies)
Will you be okay?
S'long as sun come up 'morra,
we'll be okay.
No good lookin' back, boy.
(rain pouring)
(door closes)
(boat creaking)
(water lapping gently)
MURGEY: Excuse me, Sir!
Sir!
(rain pouring)
Need a skipper?
Oo's askin'?
I am.
Do I know ya?
Do ya?
Maybe.
(low rumbling)
(baby gurgles)
What was Alan like?
Free-spirited.
Or if you're looking out
the other window,
a bloody coward who spent
his life
runnin' away.
He had his moments, though.
He'd have loved you
so much, Linsey.
(slurping)
(rock music playing)
(door closes)
-MIKE: Hiya, Jess.
-Alright?
Got summin' for yer.
It was your dad's.
Found it in some stuff
from back along.
Suits ya.
Mm...
Okay.
(music playing faintly)
Okay?
(creaking, clanking)
(clanking)
(clanging)
(bang)
(small thud)
(metal scraping)
(big splash)
Wasson?
(sniffs)
(wind picks up)
Think I'm gonna walk
the long way home.
We'll come with you.
No.
Go on, get that lot
in the freezer.
(footsteps receding rapidly)
(slow dramatic music)
(boat splashing, sloshing,
chugging)
Okay?
They going today?
Still one short.
What you gonna do?
Wait.
We don't go short-handed.
Do we?
Why don't you go, Mike?
I'm a businessman, Tina.
Not a fisherman.
(poignant music)
Can I get an advance?
Advance?
Yeah, just a few quid.
No-one's earnin' 'til
tha's turnin'.
(coin clanks)
(door opens)
Excuse me?
Can I start a tab?
LANDLADY: Sorry pard.
I've got a job.
I just ain't been paid yet.
JESS: What's your job?
Fisherman.
Oh yeah?
Deckhand.
I'll get you a drink,
Mr Fisherman.
Thanks.
(soft background music)
Put it on my tab.
You abn' got a tab, Jess.
Can I start one?
No, Jess.
Oh, lend us some money.
Charmin'.
My dad was a fisherman.
Wodn'e, Mum?
'Cept we don't talk about it.
Do we?
'Ome time idn' it, Jess?
Oh well...
We'll have a drink
when you come back.
Liam.
If you come back.
Now you'll have to come back.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
Yeah?
'Cause I want my cap back.
(door closes)
Take care out there.
Okay.
Thanks!
(door opens)
(door closes)
(sombre music)
(bird squawking)
(wings fluttering)
(crow caws)
I think they're gonna start
fishing again.
Really?
(crow caws)
(low whooshing)
Summin's goin' on.
(roof caves in)
(loud crash)
(thud)
(rubble crumbling)
(wind blowing outside)
(thunder rumbling)
(heavy rain falling)
(echoing drips)
(dramatic music)
JESS: Oo's boat is it?
TINA: Dunno.
Up the line?
Dunno.
Yes, you do.
I don't.
No snow.
You always know.
Should snow for Christmas.
You know everythin'.
Bloody...orifice
of knowledge, you are.
(laughs)
What?
(baby grumbles)
All I know is, it ent goin'
nowhere any time soon.
How come?
They ent got the crew.
They have.
They abn'.
'E looked like crew t'me.
They're one short.
No, they ent.
(baby gurgles)
(dramatic music)
(rustling)
EMILY: We're coming with you.
NICK: I don't want you to come.
We wanna see you off.
I don't want you to.
Stay 'ere in the warm.
I'll be back in a coupla days.
I'll be countin'.
See ya.
Close the door.
(ominous music)
That boat was lost.
You remember.
She went down short-'anded,
didn' she?
You let 'em down.
You never forgiv'd y'self.
My beautiful boy.
(footsteps receding)
Don't do it to us again.
Me and your dad can't go
through it again.
(poignant music)
(birds twittering)
(door opens)
(waves splashing)
Everyone's be'ind ya, Murgey.
Fair seas.
An' bring the fish back.
(seagulls crying)
(boat rumbling)
(wood clattering)
Alright, my friend?
(bag thunks)
Get the bowline!
MIKE: I got 'n.
(engine roars)
(wake splashes gently)
(boat horn sounding)
(poignant music continues)
See y'soon, m'darlin'.
(quiet rumbling)
(sinister music)
(ominous music)
(fishing gear clanking)
(creaking, rumbling)
(clanking, straining)
Tha's all there is to it.
-Then what?
-And then...
we 'ope...
that weem on the fish.
An' the net comes up full.
Turn that one.
(cranking)
Teamwork, boys.
Simple as that.
(engine rumbling)
(waves splashing)
What about them?
Don't use they.
What do you use?
Never you mind.
Guttin' knife.
We d'cut from 'ed to asshole.
Right?
'Ed to asshole.
Fish...goes in the box.
Ice.
Lots of it.
(ice clanking)
When they'm done,
stack 'em over there.
An' when they'm at the roof,
we go 'ome!
Well, let's get cracking then.
MURGEY: 'Old y'four leggers,
bud!
Fish don't eat 'til after tea.
(ice clinking)
(whistling)
(cutlery, crockery clanking)
Thank you, Decky.
You'll make yourself
a nice little wife
for someone one day.
You married?
Few times.
Family man?
It's complicated.
Thankfully 'tis simple
out 'ere, boys.
Let's shoot that net.
(dramatic music)
(rumbling, clanking)
(rumbling, scraping)
(sea gushing)
(clanking)
(squeaking)
(rumbling)
(suspenseful music)
♪ Mar hweg deg del dyv hi ♪
♪ An rosen wynn ♪
♪ Mar splann mar vryntin ♪
♪ A dhre dha gov omma dhe-vy ♪
♪ Kynsa pan welis ow hwegol ♪
♪ Yth es ta mar deg avel ros ♪
♪ Mes lemmyn mar dhisliw
dha vejeth ♪
♪ Mar wynn avel rosen
mayth os ♪
♪ My 'gar an rosen wynn ♪
♪ Mar hweg,
mar deg del dyv hi ♪
♪ An rosen wynn ♪
♪ Mar splann mar vryntin ♪
♪ A dhre dha gov omma dhe-vy ♪
MRS RICHARDS: That boat
was lost.
(pots clanging)
Haulin' time, boys!
(winches clanging)
(loud creaking)
C'mon boys!
Open it!
(fish splosh)
'Ed to asshole, remember?
'Ed to asshole.
Yes?
-Yes.
-Yes!
Thought you lot were all
natural fishermen?
(gulls crying)
(engine rumbles)
(creaking, clanging)
You boys get an 'our's shut eye.
Don't 'e ever sleep?
Legend.
(rhythmic background clanging)
(ominous music)
(fish sploshing)
(sea lapping)
(seagulls squawking)
(ice clattering)
MURGEY: Tha's it!
Is that it?
'Old's full, ent it?
Well, yeah.
Can't take no more.
(thumps)
'Ome t'Mother.
Back to that boozer.
Can't wait.
Can't wait to be 'ome again.
Can't wait to be back out again!
Dunno about that.
Only one thing worse than being
at sea boy, anyhow.
(clank)
(ice clattering)
Oh, yeah?
Not being at sea.
(laughs)
(laughs) Awww...
(poignant music)
(gull cries)
(engine chugging)
(boat horn blares)
(creaking)
'Kin' 'ell!
Ugh...
(exhales)
(engine chugging)
(wake splashing)
(boat horn blares)
(poignant music intensifies)
Talk of the bleddy village
we'll be.
We're gonna set the market.
Get below, boys. We got
'elluva lotta fish to land.
(crates scraping)
Last one.
Done.
Pint?
No thanks.
Just wanna get home.
Suit yourself.
You comin'?
No.
You boys enjoy yourselves.
Alright.
See you later.
Hup!
See y'morra.
(dramatic music)
(background chatter)
(seagulls crying)
(low rumbling, whooshing)
(birds cooing)
See y'morra.
Yeah.
Oh, no you don't!
Gonna go spend
the 'ousekeepin' then?
-Eh?
-You 'erd.
I...I ain't even been paid yet.
Like 'ell! Jus' like las' time?
Jus' like ev'ry time?
Gonna come back 'ventually,
were ya?
-What?
-Daddy?
Give it 'er then!
Alan.
Let's get Daddy 'ome before
'e gets himself in more trouble.
Come on!
(troubling music)
(game machine beeps)
(background music)
(music intensifies)
(background chatter)
What the fuck?
(music intensifies further)
(loud pub chatter)
What the fuck?
Hiya.
Welcome 'ome, boy!
Get y'old man a pint, will yer?
Mr Richards?
Good trip?
(door squeaks)
Please yourself.
Let's get 'ome, then.
(birds twittering)
Tea's ready. Immersion's on.
Okay?
(footsteps running)
(traffic rumbling)
(doorknob rattling)
Emily?
(dog barking)
Where've they gone?
Where's who gone?
-Where are they?
-Who?
No. What the fuck's going on?
-Wasson boy?
-No, tell me...
(crashing, struggling)
-Mike!
-(grunts)
-Michael!
-Calm down!
-'S'alright, Mike.
Leave 'im be.
Luke!
Is this a fuckin' joke?
Luke?
Luke's dead.
(clock ticking)
He jumped off Lurgan 'ed.
My name is Nick Dyer.
I was born in 1996.
Mr Richards, I live next door.
I'll run y'bath.
Do you not remember?
Have you taken something?
You gave me the job
three days ago.
Luke, y'bin on the boat
three year, boy.
Luke, love.
Wha'?
Three years?
I abn'.
When's the last time you slept?
I need the money
to fix the roof.
Denver d'work
the boys quite 'ard.
(clock stops ticking)
Denver?
(sizzling)
Mum?
-Yes, Jess?
Is Daddy stayin'?
Dunno.
Y'stayin'?
I dunno.
(spoon clanks)
(door closes)
(tap dripping)
(knocking on door)
MRS RICHARDS: You alright
in there?
Yeah.
Tea's ready.
(footsteps receding)
(water continues dripping)
(splashing)
(bath draining)
(tap dripping)
(stairs creaking)
(clock ticking)
I'm not 'ungry.
Thanks.
I'm just gonna go bed, I think.
Okay, m'darlin'.
(stairs creaking)
(poignant music)
(electronic bleep)
(clock ticking)
(groans)
(crash)
MRS RICHARDS: That boat
was lost.
You never forgived yourself...
She went down short-handed,
didn't she?
You let 'em down.
-(gasps)
(footsteps)
(dramatic music)
(lights flicker)
Mornin' Alan.
(seagulls squawking)
(crate crashing)
(groans)
What the fuck is going on?
Fucked if I know.
(hooting)
(truck rumbling)
'Right boys?
C'mon!
Got ya money.
(fingers tapping)
(exhaust chugging)
(foot tapping)
(engine idling)
C'mon.
(boats chugging)
(seagulls crying)
There you go, boys.
Don't put it all in the pub.
Supplies.
Go get the shoppin', boys.
NICK: The boat'll get us home.
It has to.
It got us 'ere.
We just go out there again,
and when we come back,
it'll all be back to normal.
Money's good anyhow.
Hi, Daddy.
Hi.
Sorry, er...
There was some stuff
that needed doing on the boat.
That true, Luke Richards?
You wouldn' tell me though
if it wodn', would yer?
Thick as bleddy shit, you two.
(money rustling)
Thanks.
See you in a few days.
LITTLE JESS: Bye!
Daddy?
You forgot your cap.
(whooshing)
(fish slopping)
MURGEY: Right on! Aah...
Ah...
(boat creaking)
(rhythmic banging)
(seagulls crying)
(clanking, whirring)
(rumbling)
(rhythmic banging continues)
(chains clank)
(boat creaking, straining)
(fish slopping)
(water sloshing)
(sloshing)
(baskets clattering)
(crate scrapes)
(crate bangs)
(rhythmic banging continues)
(seagull squawks)
(cutlery clatters)
Bleddy ansum that was, Decky.
Wha's 'is name?
Wha'?
Him.
Decky.
His real name.
And my real name?
Is Murgey your real name?
No.
'Tis a nickname.
Nick. Name. (laughs)
What's your real name?
'Tis lost in the wind, Sir.
That's just the way it is.
Denver?
I may be in charge
of this here vessel,
but that dun't mean I don't
appreciate you boys.
Y' doin' good.
Workin' 'ard
and 'tis much appreciated.
But jus' remember...
for every man at sea,
there's five ashore
relying on yer.
So, stay sharp.
Alright?
(inhales)
(crockery clattering)
How's she lookin' back there?
LIAM: 27 boxes.
Right on!
One more trawl?
Then 'ome t'Mother!
Weee-ooo!
(chugging, clanging)
(whirring)
(churning, creaking)
(motor chugging)
(sea sploshing)
(straining, groaning)
What is it?
Buggered!
Ugh...
(hammer clangs)
(hammering, jiggling)
(groaning)
(clatter)
(engine cuts)
(waves lap gently)
(eerie beat)
'Ere!
'S always next time!
(eerie beat)
Get that net aboard, mind.
Disaster if we lose that.
(eerie music)
(motor puttering)
Lovely trip o'fish?
'Twas.
Can't find the fish now, though.
(eerie music continues)
No, no, no, no, no.
(water dripping)
(foreboding music)
(creaking, clanking)
(background chatter)
(ice crashing)
That's it!
Alright?
Yeah.
Mother's 'ome with Jess.
Don't get involved.
Liam?
My name's not Liam.
What is it, Alan?
No! It's not fucking Alan.
(scoffs)
What is your name, then?
Don't matter no more.
(waves sloshing)
You alright?
Alright?
Comin'?
-Yew.
-Alright?
(eerie beat)
MIKE: Three's a crowd.
NICK: I warned him.
You!
(ominous beat)
MIKE: You know, there's always
a wanker on the crew.
An' if you can't spot'm,
can't spot'm...
then it must be you.
An' if you can't spot'm,
can't spot'm...
Get this sorted, shall us?
You should get yourself
a girlfriend.
Get this sorted, shall us?
An' if you can't spot'm...
(electronic whirring)
(low rumble)
(clattering)
(truck engine starts)
(gears grind)
(engine revs)
(gravel churns, crunches)
(leaves rustling)
(tyres screeching)
(engine rumbling)
(grass rustling)
(high tempo music)
(engine revving furiously)
MRS RICHARDS: You never
forgived yourself.
(sinister beat)
Aaaargh!
(hissing)
On...deck...now!
Now!
Storm comin'!
Aaargh!
(dramatic music)
(groans)
(boat chugging)
(footsteps approaching)
(groans)
Alright, Steve McQueen?
Yeah, you?
Yeah.
You have fun las' night?
Yeah?
Yeah.
Had a few at the pub, then...
home for an early night.
'Ome?
You know what I mean.
You forgotten she thinks
you're someone else?
I am someone else...
for now.
What you're doin's
prob'ly illegal.
An' if it idn',
it's still pretty bleak.
(dark music)
(boat rumbling)
(gutting knife squelching)
(seagull squawking)
Push our luck, shall us, boys?
Quick trawl before
the weather 'its.
Yeeeooooww!
(boat chugging)
(thunder rumbles)
(heavy rain pelts down)
(wind howls)
(thunder cracks)
(lamp rattling)
(rain thrashing)
(eerie music)
(water sloshing)
(rumbling, clattering, breaking)
Here she comes!
(wave crashes)
(shouts) 'Old on, boys!
(wave crashes violently)
(clattering, clanging)
(another wave crashes)
(clattering)
Watch out!
(wave crashes)
(clattering, shattering)
(creaking, splashing)
MURGEY: Uh...c'mon...
Jammed solid...
C'mon, ya fuck!
Argh!
(rain pelting)
(creaking, screeching)
Tight as a bloody drum!
-Christ!
-What?!
Warp's gone round the prop!
What's that mean?!
We're dead in the water, boys!
(wave crashing)
(eerie music)
Goin' broadside, we are!
(loud creaking)
If we don't free that prop...
(another wave crashes)
...we're done for!
(wave crashes)
Hey!
(screeching)
(gurgling)
(ominous music)
Grab on!
Grab hold of it!
-Argh!
(heart beats)
(splashing, gurgling)
(splashing)
(gasping)
C'mon!
C'mon.
Give me your hand!
(rattling, clattering)
There!
(creaking, clattering)
(rain pouring)
(creaking, metal screeching)
Argh.
(groans)
(ominous music)
(crack, snap)
(creaking, engine rumbles)
(axe clatters)
(engine rumbling)
(waves crashing)
Right on!
(chaotic noise stills)
Right.
'Ome t'Mother.
No net, no fish.
Heroes to zeroes
in a dozen tides.
Weem gonna
be the talk of the land.
(pensive music)
(scratching)
(whooshing)
(low rumble)
LIAM: Can I go?
MURGEY: Aye, go on.
Alright, don't miss me.
Lash-up!
You ent on your own.
Hi.
Giz a kiss.
(dramatic music)
Even the liars
ent catching nuthin'.
Least you're all in one piece.
You catch 'er 'old tight!
Hello, darling!
Don't let her go, mind.
There ya go.
Thanks, Daddy.
One, two, three, wahey!...
(confounding music)
(whooshing)
(dark beat)
(dramatic music)
(car engine starts)
TV: 73 degrees Fahrenheit.
Light winds.
It will feel very pleasant.
That's the forecast.
This is the summary.
Coming up shortly,
tonight's movie...
Mineral Point.
Every time you turn
on a light
or turn the heating up
at night...
(TV continues in background)
Can I tell you something?
Can I?
Madder do 'e?
What?
Does it matter?
Not sure.
Le's leave it unsaid, then.
(jingle plays on television)
You're 'ere now.
Tha's all that matters.
(foreboding music)
(knocking on door)
(muffled) Need y'ousekeepin',
boy.
(muffled) Please come 'ome,
my darlin'.
MR RICHARDS: Can't go campin'
out in there forever!
(tinkling music)
NICK: Liam?
Liam!
(dramatic music)
MRS RICHARDS: You remember.
(gasps)
(background chatter fades in)
(dramatic music)
Wha's goin' on?
What's it look like?
(net straining)
(sinister music)
(fish crashing)
Wah ho!
C'mon, boy! Let's see if
we can keep up with 'e.
(rhythmic thumping)
(rhythmic thumping continues)
That it?
That it?!
That's it.
(rhythmic thumping continues)
MURGEY: We're gonna crack on.
Keep fishin'.
The 'old's full.
Plenty a room on deck.
(sighs)
We 'ad a vote.
No, we didn't.
Didn't need one.
We got a majority.
Ready to shoot in ten.
(metal scraping, straining)
(waves lapping)
(rhythmic thumping continues)
(screeching intensifies)
(screeching stops)
(low rumbling fades in)
(boat horn blares)
(engine chugging)
(creaking, scraping)
(clang)
(camera clicks)
(low whoosh)
(dramatic music)
Look at it.
Can't you see wha's going on?
It's us.
They don't catch fish
unless we catch fish.
They're depending on us.
Nice to be needed.
(waves lapping)
(seagulls crying)
(clankiing)
Liam...
(creaking)
Listen.
Hi.
-Alright?
-Mm.
-Hello.
-Liam...
Why did they all come out
to make up a new net?
We call it community.
Liam.
Don't go 'ome with her.
Get fucked.
-Liam!
-My name's not Liam!
I know it ent.
It idn' Alan either.
-Luke!
I'm not Luke!
Take your hand off me.
You're not him.
You don't even know him.
Last chance.
-Daddy...
-Alan...
I'm sorry. He's not your dad.
He's just not.
It's okay.
It's okay, Daddy's here.
(whooshing)
Daddy!
(headbutt)
Ugh...
NICK: We all die, don't we?
The boat's lost.
Mrs Richards told me.
I'll let you go short-'anded.
Then you don't come 'ome.
And it'll be my fault.
(solemn music)
(bee buzzing)
(waves lapping)
(whooshing)
(solemn music continues)
(waves crashing)
(Nick sobs)
(leaves rustling)
(gate opens, closes)
(footsteps approaching)
(birds twittering)
(door opens)
(door shuts)
(clock ticking)
Breakfast?
Look at you.
(deep breath)
You oughta take better care.
If anything happened to you.
My beautiful boy.
I'm here.
I'm gonna go now.
Alright, my love.
Good for you.
(envelope rustling)
(bag zips shut)
(clock ticking stops)
MR RICHARDS: Will you be okay?
S'long as the sun come
up 'morra, we'll be fine.
No good lookin' back, boy.
See y'soon, m'darlin'.
(door shuts)
(boat chugging)
(water lapping)
Mornin' Denver!
Don't worry.
She always comes back.
(car door closes)
Here he is.
(metal creaking, clanking)
'Right, 'ansum?
Back onboard?
That alright?
Still short 'anded, though.
(sniffs)
'Tis dyin' on the vine, Michael.
Aye, aye!
It's not my fault!
Wasson?!
Really wasn't this time!
It's bloody Tina.
MURGEY: Get the bowline!
She's been puking
since she woke up.
I had to sort Jess.
Oh yeah?
Pukin' in the mornin'?
Yeah.
What? She was!
Bein' sick, is she?
Yeah.
(ropes thunk)
Bein' sick in the morning,
is she?
Yeah!
Fuck!
(boat creaking, groaning)
(everything grows silent)
(whooshing)
(distorted) C'mon, Luke.
Get goin'.
(static whisper)
There's no time.
(static interference)
(boat horn blares)
(muffled thud)
(boat's engine starts up)
(dramatic music)
(slow dramatic music)